# 家常版的家常版的家常版的三句啊
Homemade, homemade, homemade, I will say it three times in a row.
# 酱汤羊蝎子
Lamb Spine Hot Pot in Bean Sauce.
# 老冯呢 我给大家介绍一下
Let me introduce to you guys. This is Feng.
# 全国有了二十多家店的
Has more than 20 restaurants around China,
# 老冯烤羊蝎子 他就是创始人
he is the founder of Feng's Lamb Spine.
# 又是二伯的徒弟 又是我的传承人
He is also Er Bai's disciple, and my successor.
# 话不多说 赶紧干活
Let's get to work!
# 这羊蝎子泡了几个小时
Those lamb spines have been soaked in water for hours.
# 泡了六个小时 泡掉它的血水
Six hours, this will remove the blood from the lamb.
# 咱们凉水下锅么 现在就可以下了
Do we just put those in while the water is cold? Yes.
# 据说啊 在内蒙做羊肉人家不焯水
In Inner Mongolia, people cook lamb without even parboiling.
# 直接炖撇沫子
Just simmer it right away and remove the blood foam.
# 我们要是说现宰的羊可以这么做
Yes, but this only works for freshly-butchered lamb.
# 现在基本上都宰完了进冷库冻了
Most of the lambs nowadays, however, will be refrigerated after butchering.
# 冻完了之后这肉的颜色
Doing so will affect the lamb's color,
# 还有腥膻味它会加重 说的有道理
and intensify the taints. Yes, you are right.
# 那你这个汆羊蝎子不搁点别的料么
Aren't we going to add any spicies?
# 现在不用搁 第一步就是焯水
Not yet, we are just parboiling.
# 就是飞水 对
Just parboiling? Yes.
# 我不知道您注意到没注意到
I don't know if you have noticed,
# 这个是十二块 十二块羊蝎子是三斤
There are twelve chunks of spines, which are about 1.5kg.
# 你看看 他现在拿数字了 搞数字化了
Yea, they actually use accurate measurements right now.
# 因为咱们家里边做 要是说蒙着投料
We won't know how much ingredient to add,
# 没有数字的概念它出来的味道
if we don't know exactly how much lamb we are getting.
# 肯定是 有区别的
That will make a difference, definitely.
# 我不追求别的 我就追求味道
I don't ask for much, but taste.
# 这也是我们老饭骨的精神
This is also the spirit of Lao Fan Gu.
# 味道为王是不是
Taste is the key.
# 现在羊蝎子该逐步的往外出血沫了
Now, the blood foams are coming out of the spines,
# 还有一股味儿呢
along with an unpleasant smell.
# 我要如果做羊肉我是肯定搁醋的
I will add vinegar for sure，
# 我飞水直接就把它拿下去了
when parboiling.
# 您教的这个我已经给它运用上了
I have implemented what you have taught me.
# 现在这步咱们打完这个沫之后
After we clean up the blood foams,
# 再把您这个醋搁进去
we will add some vinegar.
# 然后它再开了 再挥发一下
Not it starts to boil, we will let it volatilize further,
# 要把羊肉的膻味邪味拿的干净一点
removing the taint even more.
# 得把沫子打一下 打完了
We have to clean up the blood foams.
# 只有大火的时候打沫子才打的干净
It is best to clean the foams on high heat.
# 这个羊蝎子要是我们在店里边做
If I were to cook lamb spines in my restaurant,
# 它得照着半个小时到四十分钟
they have to be parboiled for at least 30 to 40 minutes,
# 连续不断的打沫子
while cleaning up the foams constantly.
# 那我现在就给你倒上 您看着搁
Now I will add vinegar. Sure.
# 我看这么多就够了
I think this should be enough.
# 你看这浑劲儿看见没有
See? All the foams
# 全给它拿出来了
are coming out.
# 它还有什么道理再膻呢
There will be no taint at all in our lamb.
# 一会我会教大家炒一个酱
Later, I will teach you guys how to make a sauce for this dish.
# 这个口味不但我能掌握
Now only I can master the taste,
# 只要咱们教了这个之后
if you do what I teach you,
# 每个人 你喜欢吃什么口味
no matter what flavor you like,
# 最后定味儿的时候 炒酱这一步
you can make any type of sauce
# 您可以按照自己的个人喜好
base on your preference.
# 能做出各式各样的羊蝎子的味道
And therefore you can make various favors' lamb spines.
# 那就这样就行了啊 现在可以了
The lambs should be good now.
# 用热水冲一下 要洗
We have to rinse them under hot water.
# 咱家里边吃一定要把这个血沫
If we cook lamb spine at home,
# 洗的干干净净的 你看看特别干净
we have to clean up the blood foams completely. See they are so clean.
# 现在北京做羊蝎子的也不少
There are a lot of restaurants in Beijing that make lamb spines how pot.
# 它是外来货 羊蝎子是从天津传过来的
However, this dish came from Tianjin.
# 对从天津 但是从最早也是从内蒙
Yes, but it originates in Inner Mongolia.
# 咱们现在弄好了啊
Now we are done with the spines.
# 您看啊 这儿有几款料
As you can see, we have some spices here.
# 有白芷 有良姜 有胡椒的这
We have angelica roots, galangals, and peppercorns.
# 就放这三味料就可以了
Those three.
# 搁几个干辣椒 捏几个花椒粒 好 够了
We can also put in some dried chili pepper, and some Sichuan peppercorns.
# 一共是五味料 好了这咱就够了
So we will have a total of five different spices.
# 然后加水 咱用矿泉水 可以
And then, add some water. We will use spring water. Sure
# 咱家里边吃咱要吃的讲究一点么
We have to be fastidious in our home.
# 这水只要能给他没过来就行
The water has to immerse the spices.
# 羊肉呢我建议还是
As for the lamb spines,
# 按照（高压锅）这个时间三十分钟
we will cook them in a pressure cooker for 30 minutes.
# 因为它是带骨头的东西
Since spines have bones,
# 因为咱们要让它脱骨
this process will sepearate the meat and the bones.
# 说的太对了 那咱们炒酱
Exactly! Now let's make the sauce.
# 网友们 今天咱们做个羊蝎子啊
Guys, today we are making lamb spine hot pot.
# 咱们老冯是达人啊 跟你老冯一起学
And Feng is such a master at making this dish, you have to learn from him.
# 家常版的家常版的家常版的三句啊
Homemade, homemade, homemade, I will say it three times in a row.
# 酱汤羊蝎子
Lamb Spine Hot Pot in Bean Sauce.
# 因为这个油可以量大一点
We can add a generous amount of oil,
# 它待会要涮菜 油大一点不碍事
since we will use it to fry our spices.
# 这个油不要太热下去 让它凉一点
We don't have to wait until the oil heats up thoroughly.
# 慢煸 煸出葱姜的香气
Just slowly fry them untio aromatic.
# 你说说刚才你放那几味料是起什么作用的
Can you tell us the purpose of each spice?
# 白芷是增香的 良姜是去腥膻味的
angelica roots creates aroma, galangal removes the taints.
# 这里边最主要的料是胡椒 去腥解腻
Peppercorns will cut down the grease of the lamb.
# 这次我放的可不是胡椒粉 是胡椒粒
I am using peppercorns instead of powder.
# 白胡椒粒
White peppercorns.
# 好 这葱见黄了 变成金黄色了
Good, the green onions are turning golden.
# 葱姜不炸 酱不够香么
If we don't fry the green onions and ginger, the sauce won't be fragrant enough.
# 这个酱有一点门道
This sauce is special.
# 我倒一半 回头您尝一口
You should taste it.
# 您给品品这酱的味道 有点意思
You try it. Hm, interesting.
# 这个酱这样炒一下就可以了
We just fry the sauce like this.
# 不要炒的太过 它的香味一出来就可以了
Don't overcook it as long as it turns fragrant.
# 现在这样咱就可以放水了
Now, we can add water.
# 长白山矿泉水 行了
Paektu Mountain Spring Water. Good.
# 这个酱汁咱就算熬好了
And we are done with the sauce.
# 最后咱们就是一个调味的过程
Lastly, we will start seasoning.
# 这个酱是由三款酱组成的
This sauce is a combination of three other different sauces.
# 黄豆酱 蚝油 还有一款最关键的柱候酱
Yellow bean paste, oyster sauce, and Zhuhou sauce.
# 但是柱候酱的量要小一些
Remember, we can't add too much Zhuhou sauce.
# 咱们今天吃的是酱汤的
Since we are making bean sauce lamb spine,
# 是以鲜味黄豆酱为主的
the flavor should be centered around the yellow bean sauce.
# 有几款香料是为了增加酱香的
We have some other spices to enhance the fragrance.
# 八角 小茴香 干姜片 桂皮 丁香
Star anise, fennel seeds, dried ginger slices, cinnamons, and cloves.
# 在超市里边都能买的着
You can find them in a grocery store.
# 这几款是根据咱们自己的口味来调
You can adjust the amount of each spice base on your own preference.
# 料也不要太多 打碎了给它放到酱里边
However, don't add too much. We will blend them and add into the sauce.
# 调到一起就行了 最好呢就是
We better put all of them together.
# 打碎了之后 调到酱里边给它焖两分钟
After blending the spices, we will add them in the sauce and simmer for two minutes.
# 羊蝎子压熟了 然后再合到那个汤里边
After the spines finish cooking, we will add the sauce into the lamb broth.
# 这点儿也差不多了 咱羊肉也该出锅了
The lamb is almost done.
# 嘿 好 咱们起出来
Good. Let's take them out.
# 您一块一块给它拣出来就成
You can take them out one by one.
# 一共十二块 别到时候炖完了剩十一块
There should be 12 pieces total.
# 时间火候掌握的刚刚好
Time and heat are just right.
# 你看 有弹性而且还脱骨
See, the meat is seperated from the bones.
# 一杵进去了 这就叫正好
I can even stick a chopstick in. This is perfection.
# 放心吧 好太棒了
It's so good.
# 老饭骨所有的人干活都细
Everyone in Lao Fan Gu works with responsibility and carefulness.
# 今天咱们把这个原汤加进去
Today, we will add the lamb broth into the sauce,
# 好吧 因为咱们这没有现成的骨汤
since we don't have pre-made stock,
# 再加水这味儿就淡了
and adding water will dilute the flavor.
# 我不要上边这层油
I don't want the oil on the surface.
# （汤面）这就宽了
Now the soup surface is getting broad.
# 这回呢咱们调味 先不放盐
As for seasoning, we won't add salt yet.
# 您先尝一下味道
You should taste it first.
# 因为咱们这个酱它本身就有咸味
Our sauce is salty already.
# 相信三叔的力量 一勺半
Trust San Shu, one and a half tablespoon of salt is enough.
# 稍微的给一点颜色（老抽）
Add some dark soysauce to give it some color.
# 因为这个汤色咱们不要它太红
The broth shouldn't be too dark right now,
# 因为这酱的颜色越煮越（深）
because the sauce gets darker the longer we boil it.
# 现在咱这个羊蝎子小火慢炖二十分钟
Now we will simmer the spines on low heat for 20 minutes.
# 然后现在还有一个最关键的一步
Here comes a key step.
# 您喜欢吃辣么
Do you like spicy food?
# 我要借它那个辣来压羊肉的膻味
I will use the spiciness to compensate the lamb's taints.
# 这个小米辣不要切粒太大了
Remember, don't cut the "Xiaomila" chili pepper too big.
# 它挥发不出来辣味
Cutting them too big won't bring out the spiciness.
# 一定切小薄圈 要精细点
We have to cut them into small, thing rings.
# 小火慢炖 关小火 现在搁进去了啊
Turn off the stove and add in the chili.
# 可以 最后的一招我得说说了
Nice. Now comes the final step.
# 您看看这是什么 我看了半天像咖喱
Do you know what this is? It looks like curry chunks.
# 好 放在里边就可以了 这就是对了
Add the curry chunks in.
# 今天到您这儿来拍这个视频呢
Today I am comming here to make this video.
# 咱们得拿出点干货来
So I have to teach you some real cooking skills.
# 三叔您看咱们做这个羊蝎子
San Shu, as for this dish, I have taught everything I can to the audience,
# 我可一点没保留啊
with nothing else left.
# 按照您的要求 一定要说干货
As you mentioned, real skill.
# 老饭骨做任何菜
Any dish that Lao Fan Gu makes,
# 必须以强大的心态 正能量
must come from the chef's positive attitude and energy,
# 来这锅台展示他的手艺
to show his skill
# 我们不许有瑕疵 在这里留一手
We won't allow any mistakes or reservation.
# 网友又不是傻子 我没必要留
Our audience aren't dumb. Yea, and I don't need to reserve anything.
# 四弟曾经说句话 味道就是王道
Si Di once said: Taste is the key.
# 我们做的就是味道
And we are aiming for better tastes of each dish.
# 再说四弟很帅啊
And, by the way, Si Di is quite handsome.
# 出锅吧 别砍啦 太棒啦
Well that's enough chatting. Let's take out the spines. Looks amazing.
# 我教大家来检验这羊蝎子合格不合格
Let me tell how to examine the spine's quality.
# 无论它怎么呢开锅 它清汤的不会乱
The broth should be clear all the time.
# 没那么多沫子 上面是油啊
There are grease on the surface, not blood foams.
# 然后它开起来之后你看它汤汁的粘稠度
You see the stickness of the broth,
# 还有透亮度 你看看
and transparency. See?
# 您就是加什么汤 怎么加
You can add as many broth as you prefer,
# 它也不会澥 好 灭火
without breaking it down. We can turn off the stove.
# 现在这个羊蝎子
Now,
# 假如再搁到汤里边泡半小时 更好吃
if we soak the spines in this sauce for an extra 30 minutes, they will taste even better.
# import ending.srt 00:08:10,000